A Finding Aid to the Anton Refregier Papers, circa 1900-circa 1990, in the Archives of American Art AAA.refranto
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, 1912-circa 1990s; Series 2; 10.4 Linear feet Boxes 1-11, 36, OVs 38, 45
  - Alphabetical Correspondence, 1930s-1982; 2.3
    - Soviet Union (Box 9)
      - Children, Letters and Camp Artek, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, circa 1950s-1976; (3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 2-4)
      - Cost of Living Estimates, circa 1960s (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Payment Records, circa 1969 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Visit, 1965-1966 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Visit, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Visit, 1971-1974 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Visit, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Visit to Azerbaijan, circa 1967-1973 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Soviet Woman Magazine Drawing, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Spanish Refugee Committee, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - State University of New York Television Production Visuals, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Statements, 1950s (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Stratford Factors, 1960-1961 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Submissions to Publications, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Syracuse University Film Division Film, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Trademark, Gay Blades Ice Skating Rink, 1938-1939; (Oversized material housed in Box 36) (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Ulster County Community College, 1965-1970 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - United Nations Missions, circa 1960-1969 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - United States Department of the Interior, Grand Coulee Dam, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - University of Alabama Library, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - University of Arkansas, Visiting Artist, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Weinstein, Abraham B., 1958-1960 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - West Hempstead Public Schools, 1960-1961 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Woodstock Artists Association, Inc., 1940s-1970s; (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 27-28)
      (includes sketches by Refregier; 1963 records deal with Rockwell Kent's 80th birthday celebration)
    - Woodstock Artists Association, Cultural Commission, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Woodstock Elementary School, "Artist in Residence,", 1973 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Woodstock Press Cards, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Works Progress Administration, 1930s-1950s; (3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 32-34)
    - Works Progress Administration, Printed Material, circa 1930s (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - World Council of Peace, 1949-1961; (5 folders) (Box 9, Folder 36-40)
    - World Council of Peace, 1962-1975; (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
    - World Council of Peace (Box 10)
      - Address Lists, circa 1950s (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Cultural Commission, 1966, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Printed Material on Vietnam, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Stockholm Trip, 1959-1960 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - World Congress for General Disarmament and Peace, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - World Congress for Peace, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - World Congress for Peace, Helsinki, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Oversized, Illustrations, Vanguard Records, circa 1959-1961; (Oversized material from Box 7) (Box 36)
    - Oversized, Trademark, Gay Blades Ice Skating Rink, 1938-1939; (Oversized material from Box 9) (Box 36)
    - Oversized, Cookery Lafayette, Inc., 1955-1970; (Oversized material from Box 6) (Box OV 38)
    - Oversized, Covington Fabrics, 1955-1956; (Oversized material from Box 6) (Box OV 38)
    - Oversized, New York Shipbuilding Corporation, 1950-1959; (Oversized material from Box 7) (Box OV 38)
    - Oversized, Associated American Artists Galleries from Box 6 (Box OV 45)
    - Greeting Cards, circa 1940s-circa 1970s; 2.4
      This series contains greeting cards, primarily seasonal, received by Refregier and his family. The first group of 13 folders contains many homemade cards and includes original artwork by artists such as Emmy Lou Packard and Byron Randall, and one greeting recorded on a phonograph record.
      - Greeting Cards, circa 1940s-circa 1970s; (13 folders) (Box 10, Folder 10-22)
      - Greeting Cards, circa 1940s-circa 1970s; (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 23-24)
      - Greeting Cards, circa 1940s-circa 1970s; (12 folders) (Box 11, Folder 1-12)
      - Scrapbook of Greeting Cards, 1960s (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Oversized, Scrapbook of Greeting Cards from Box 11, 1960s (Box OV 45)
        Oversized material from Box 11
- Writings, circa 1930s-circa 1970s; Series 3; 3.3 Linear feet Boxes 11-14, OV 45
  This series contains primarily drafts of many unpublished essays and autobiographical writings by Refregier, in addition to copies of several of his published works including Natural Figure Drawing, An Artists Journey and Sketches of the Soviet Union. Typescript drafts of "Diary of a Mural" appear to document Refregier's experience while working on his mural for the Rincon Annex Post Office.
  The series is arranged as 2 subseries:
  3.1: Writings by Refregier, circa 1930s-circa 1970s
  3.2: Writings by Others, circa 1930s-circa 1970s
  - Writings by Refregier, circa 1930s-circa 1970s; 3.1
    Writings include typescripts, notes, layout material including sketches and photographs, and published copies of books. Records relating to Art in Architecture include photos of Refregier
    See Appendix for a partial list of the writings not listed individually in this series.
    Writings by Refregier are arranged in rough chronological order, with groups of writings that appear to be from the same decade grouped at the beginning of the files for that decade. A partial list of the writings in the group files can be found in the Appendix.
    Writings by Refregier Not Listed Individually
    "American Artists Gift Exhibition," circa 1940s-circa 1970s
    "An Art Exhibition," circa 1940s-circa 1970s
    "Art Student," circa 1940s-circa 1970s
    "Artist Should Be consulted," circa 1940s-circa 1970s
    "Cooking for Pleasure," circa 1940s-circa 1970s
    Decorating with sandblasting, circa 1940s-circa 1970s
    Line and drawing, circa 1940s-circa 1970s
    "Message to the National Mural Conference," circa 1940s-circa 1970s
    Need to establish a federal program with the power to give grants for art and culture, circa 1940s-circa 1970s
    Scottsboro Ballet, circa 1940s-circa 1970s
    "Spring in New York City," circa 1940s-circa 1970s
    "Artists Life in the U.S.," 1950s
    "Having a Wonderful Time," 1950s
    "Murals for your Home," 1950s
    Picasso, 1950s
    Rockwell Kent's 75th anniversary, 1950s
    "School Architecture," 1950s
    "Art for our Schools," 1960s
    "Eugene Morley," 1960s
    "Karl Kanol," 1960s
    "Harvey Fite," 1960s
    Letter to Editor re: WPA, 1960s
    Re: Soviet artists, 1960s
    "Spring in New York City"
    "Statement in Connection with Forthcoming Exhibition in Moscow," 1960s
    "A Draft of an Article on the Cultural Scene-USA," 1970s
    "An Artist's Journey to Mexico" (includes photo of artist Pablo O'Higgins), 1970s
    Bernal, John Desmond, 1970s
    "Cathy," 1970s
    Dedication to Rockwell Kent, 1970s
    "My Friend David," 1970s
    "Salaspil," 1970s
    Tribute to Philip Evergood, 1973
    Painting "The Strike" (San Francisco Waterfront Strike painted in 1934), 1973
    Article for Soviet Union magazine Rovesnick, 1977
    Daily World question and answer page, 1977
    Book review of Towards a People's Art: The Contemporary Mural Movement, 1977
    - Writings, circa 1940s-circa 1970s; (6 folders) (Box 11, Folder 14-19)
    - Writings, 1930s (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - "Mural Painting in America,", 1944 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Writings, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Writings, 1950s (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - "An Artist's Journey to a New World," layout copy, circa 1950s (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - "Diary of a Mural,", circa 1950s; (4 folders) (Box 12, Folder 4-7)
    - "Diary of a Mural," Related Material, circa 1950s (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Statement to Woodstock Artists Association regarding journal Reality, circa 1953 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - "What a U.S. Artist saw in Guatemala,", 1953-1956 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - New York State Art Teacher's Convention Speech, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - "Guatemala," Layout copy, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - "Guatemala," Layout Copy, Related Material, 1955-1959 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Writings for Class 4-506, 1955-1956 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Lecture, Unknown, circa 1953-1957 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - "9 months"/"When A Child Is Born", circa 1958-1965 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Re: Drawing, circa 1958 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - New World Review Article, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - United States Arts Foundation Bill, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - "Buchenwald,", 1959-1960 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Writings, 1960s; (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 21-22)
    - Government Sponsorship of the Arts, 1960s (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Art in Architecture, Notes and Layout material, circa 1960s (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Art in Architecture, First Draft, circa 1960s; (4 folders) (Box 12, Folder 25-28)
    - Art in Architecture, Additional Material, circa 1960s (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Natural Figure Drawing, Second Edition, Tudor Publishing, New York, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Kingston High School Magazine Article, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Public Ownership in the U.S.A.-Goals and Priorities, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - "Responsibility of the Artist,", 1963 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - An Artist's Journey, International Publishers, New York, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      (signed hardcover with limited edition print, #36 of 50)
    - An Artist's Journey, International Publishers, New York, Paperback copy, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Soviet Diary, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Soviet Diary/"Anton Refregier's Diary", published in Woodstock Week, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Soviet Diary Possible Drafts, circa 1960s (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Tapestry Article for American Artist, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Writings and Statements, 1970s; (3 folders) (Box 13, Folder 8-10)
    - "Chile," Layout Copies, circa 1970s (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Autobiographical Typescript, Draft for 1905-1928, circa 1970s (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Autobiographical Typescript, Draft and Notes, circa 1970s (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Autobiographical Typescript, Draft and Notes "Getting Along,", circa 1970s (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Autobiographical Typescript Draft, "Up Against the Wall," Chapter 2: "America", circa 1970s (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Sketches of the Soviet Union, Typescripts, circa 1970s (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Sketches of the Soviet Union, Typescript Drafts and Notes, circa 1970s (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - "Soviet Union Stories," Typescripts Drafts, circa 1970s (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Response to New York Times Magazine Mural Article, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Writings, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Typescripts written in Moscow, 1973-1974; (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 21-22)
    - "Up Against the Wall," Typescripts, Notes, 1974; (3 folders) (Box 13, Folder 23-25)
    - "Coming Home" Typescript, circa 1974 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - "An Artist's Journey," Layout copy, circa 1975 (Box 13, Folder 27)
      (for version published in Moscow)
    - "Guatemala and Later Chile,", circa 1976 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - "Art in Defense of Peace,", 1976 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Writings, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - "A Gift of Life: A Diary of Open-Heart Surgery,", 1977 (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Sketches of the Soviet Union, Progress Publishers: Moscow, 1978; (2 hardback copies) (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Notes and Fragments, 1930s-1970s; (14 folders) (Box 14, Folder 1-14)
    - Notes, College Lectures/Courses, circa 1937 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Oversized, Art in Architecture, Notes and Layout material from Box 12, circa 1960s (Box OV 45)
  - Writings by Others, circa 1930s-circa 1970s; 3.2
    Writings by others includes primarily typescripts about Refregier and on various other subjects by authors including Howard Koch, Rockwell Kent, Walter Lowenfels, and possibly some of Refregier's students.
    - About Refregier (Box 14)
      - Chegadaev, A, "Refregier's World of Forms,", 1966 (Box 14, Folder 16)
      - Mahoney, Murrelle, circa 1960s (Box 14, Folder 17)
      - Roberts, Holand, circa 1960s (Box 14, Folder 18)
      - University of Virginia Art Museum, Essays on Refregier inspired by exhibition in 1977, circa 1977 (Box 14, Folder 19)
      - Notes on Refregier by Unidentified, circa 1960s (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Other Subjects, circa 1930s-circa 1970s; (9 folders) (Box 14, Folder 21-29)
- Diaries and Journals, 1923-1979; Series 4; 0.6 Linear feet Box 15
  Fifteen diaries and journals from circa 12 years are found in the form of typescripts and handwritten journals and day planners. Many contain sketches and were created primarily by Refregier to record travel and day-to-day activities including specific projects such as the New York World's Fair Mural in 1938. One 1923 journal is handwritten in Russian.
  Diaries are arranged chronologically, with 2 items belonging to Lila Refregier and 1 item probably belonging to Anton Refregier Jr.'s (Toto) wife, placed at the end of the series.
  - Journal, 1923 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Diary, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Diary, circa 1937-circa 1938; (2 folders) (Box 15, Folder 3-4)
  - Journal, New York World's Fair Mural, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Diaries, 1950, 1951, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Diary, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Diary and Calendar Fragment, 1957, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Journal, circa 1960s (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Journal, "Mural in the Syracuse University,", 1963 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    (contains correspondence and sketches)
  - Diary, circa 1973-1974 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Diary, Lila Refregier, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Notebook, Lila Refregier, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Diary, Wife of Anton Refregier, Jr. (Toto), circa 1960s (Box 15, Folder 14)
- Mural and Tapestry Files, circa 1930s-circa 1970s; Series 5; 3.75 Linear feet Boxes 15-18, 36, OVs 38, 45, 46, RD 42
  This series documents Refregier's work on many mural and tapestry projects for private and corporate clients such as Bowery Savings Bank, Cafe Society Uptown, Sheraton Hotels, anbd First National Bank. It also documents commissions for state and federal government agencies, including the WPA and commissions such as the post office in Plainfield, NJ, Rikers Island Prison, and the Rincon Annex Post Office. Files contain correspondence, notes, many loose sketches and cartoons, printed material and photographs. Additional records relating to these files can be found in Series 2: Correspondence.
  The series is arranged as 2 subseries, with files arranged alphabetically by name of project or subject:
  5.1: Murals, circa 1930s-circa 1970s
  5.2: Tapestries, circa 1940s-circa 1970s
  - Murals, circa 1930s-circa 1970s; 5.1
    - Abraham & Strauss Nassau, Long Island, NY, 1951-1952 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Cafe Society Uptown, 1940 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Chicago Murals, circa 1970s (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Chicopee Motor Inn, Chicopee, MA, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Continental National Bank, Lincoln, NA, Competitions, 1957-1958 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Country Club, Norfolk, VA, 1959-1969 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Covington Fabrics Corporation, 1952-1955 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - First National Bank, Tulsa, OK, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - First National Stores Inc., 1954-1959; (4 folders) (Box 15, Folder 23-26)
    - Gracie Square Hospital, New York, NY, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Greenpoint Hospital, 1930s (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Greenwich Federal Savings & Loan Association, Proposal, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Hartleys Inc., Miami, FL, 1959-1960; (Oversized material housed in OV 45) (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Hillcrest Jewish Center, 1950-1954; (2 folders; oversized material housed in OV 46, RD 42) (Box 16, Folder 2-3)
    - Hotel Americana Carnival Room, Miami Beach, FL, 1955-1957 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - International Inn, Washington, D.C., 1962 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Jewish Community Center, White Plains, New York, NY, 1956 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Junior High School, Queens, Emery Roth & Sons, 1952 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Kingston High School Mural Project, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Lessman Incorporated, 1933-1940; (2 folders; oversized material housed in Box 36, OV 46) (Box 16, Folder 9-10)
    - Lessman Incorporated, Paul Revere Room, Hotel Lexington, New York, NY, 1937-1940; (2 folders) (Box 16, Folder 11-12)
    - Local 1199 Union Building, New York, NY, 1967-1970 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Mayo Clinic Diagnostic Unit, 1951-1954 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Mayo Clinic Diagnostic Unit, Research Material, circa 1952 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Metropolitan Hospital, New York, NY, 1968-1971; (2 folders) (Box 16, Folder 16-17)
    - National Maritime Union of America, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Nebraska Capitol Building, Lincoln, NA, circa 1950s (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Nebraska Capitol Building, Lincoln, NA, Source Material, circa 1950s; (7 folders) (Box 16, Folder 20-26)
    - New York Central System, 1938; (Oversized material housed in Box 36) (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - New York Labor Temple, 1939-1940 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Orange Plaza Shoping Center, Middletown, NY, 1971-1972 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Phoenix Insurance Company, Hartford, CT, 1950-1951; (Oversized material housed in OV 38) (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - Plaza Hotel, NY, Ben Sackheim, Inc., 1962 (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Post Office, Plaindfield, NJ, 1941-1942; (Oversized material housed in Box 36) (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - Public School 146, Bronx, NY, 1957-1966 (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - Rikers Island Prison, Rikers Island, NY, 1936, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Rincon Annex Post Office, San Francisco, CA (Box 17)
      - Rincon Annex Post Office, San Francisco, CA, 1940s-1970s; (13 folders) (Box 17, Folder 2-14)
      - Mural Competition Sketchbook, 1940s (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - News Clippings, 1950s-1970s (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - Personal Statements/History, circa 1930s-circa 1960s (Box 17, Folder 17)
      - Source Material and Sketches, circa 1940s; (7 folders; oversized material housed in Box 36, OV 46) (Box 17, Folder 18-24)
    - Ritz Carlton Hotel Cocktail Lounge, 1964-1966 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - S.S. Constitution, S.S. Independence, 1950s (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - S.S. President Polk, 1940-1942 (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Sam Burt House, Brooklyn, NY, 1966-1971 (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Schoen and Hennessy, 1955-1956 (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Schroeder Hotel, Lessman Interiors, 1950-1951; (Oversized material housed in OV 38) (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Sheraton Corporation, Mexico, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Sheraton Hotels, Binghamton, NY and Dallas, TX, 1956-1959; (2 folders) (Box 18, Folder 3-4)
    - Sheraton Hotel, Philadelphia, 1955-1957; (2 folders; oversized material housed in OV 38) (Box 18, Folder 5-6)
    - Sheraton Motor Inn, New York, NY, 1961-1962; (Oversized material housed in OV 38) (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Sheraton Park Hotel, Washington D.C., 1963-1964 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Syracuse University, 1962-1963 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Tokeneke Elementary School, 1955-1956; (Oversized material housed in OV 46) (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Union News Company Thruway Restaurants, 1954-1955; (Oversized material housed in OV 46) (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Union News Company Thruway Restaurants, Light Fixtures, 1954-1955; (Oversized material housed in OV 46) (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - University of Kentucky Medical Center, 1959-1961; (2 folders) (Box 18, Folder 13-14)
    - Unknown/Miscellaneous, 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Zenith Radio Corporation, 1956-1958 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Oversized, Lessman Incorporated, 1933-1940; (Oversized material from Box 16) (Box 36)
    - Oversized, New York Central System, 1938; (Oversized material from Box 16) (Box 36)
    - Oversized, Post Office, Plaindfield, NJ, 1941-1942; (Oversized material from Box 16) (Box 36)
    - Oversized, Rincon Annex Post Office, San Francisco, CA, Source Material and Sketches, circa 1940s; (Oversized material from Box 17) (Box 36)
    - Oversized, Phoenix Insurance Company, Hartford, CT, 1950-1951; (Oversized material from Box 16) (Box OV 38)
    - Oversized, Schroeder Hotel, Lessman Interiors, 1950-1951; (Oversized material from box 18) (Box OV 38)
    - Oversized, Sheraton Hotel, Philadelphia, 1955-1957; (Oversized material from Box 18) (Box OV 38)
    - Oversized, Sheraton Motor Inn, New York, NY, 1961-1962; (Oversized material from Box 18) (Box OV 38)
    - Oversized, Hartleys Inc., Miami, FL, 1959-1960; (Oversized material from Box 16) (Box OV 45)
    - Oversized, Hillcrest Jewish Center, 1950-1954; (Oversized material from Box 16) (Box OV 46)
    - Oversized, Lessman Incorporated, 1933-1940; (Oversized material from Box 16) (Box OV 46)
    - Oversized, Rincon Annex Post Office, San Francisco, CA, Source Material and Sketches, circa 1940s; (Oversized material from Box 17) (Box OV 46)
    - Oversized, Tokeneke Elementary School, 1955-1956; (Oversized material from Box 18) (Box OV 46)
    - Oversized, Union News Company Thruway Restaurants, 1954-1955; (Oversized material from Box 18) (Box OV 46)
    - Oversized, Union News Company Thruway Restaurants, Light Fixtures, 1954-1955; (Oversized material from Box 18) (Box OV 46)
    - Oversized, Hillcrest Jewish Center, 1950-1954; (Oversized material from Box 16) (Box RD 42)
  - Tapestries, circa 1940s-circa 1970s; 5.2
    - Agents, 1971-1972 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Bowery Savings Bank, 1964-1967; (5 folders) (Box 18, Folder 18-22)
      (includes photo of Refregier)
    - Bowery Savings Bank, Promotion, 1964-1967 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Exhibition Ideas, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Fabric Samples, circa 1940s-circa 1960s (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Hester, Mary and Vasquez, Isaac, 1968-1970 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Rotron Manufacturing Company, Inc., 1962 (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Sheraton Hotel, Cleveland, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Tapestry Records, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 18, Folder 29)
- Exhibition Files, 1942-1981; Series 6; 0.6 Linear feet Boxes 18-19
  Files primarily contain correspondence and notes relating to exhibition arrangements and lists of exhibited works. Additional announcements, catalogs, invitations and exhibition reviews can be found in Series 8: Printed Material, Refregier.
  - Paintings and Mural Sketches by Anton Refregier (1942), ACA Galleries (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Anti-Fascist Drawings (1945), National Federation for Constitutional Liberties, ACA Galleries (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - "Anton Refregier" (1948), Fraymart Gallery, Los Angeles, CA (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - "San Francisco" (1949), ACA Galleries (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - "Anton Refregier, Recent Paintings" (1953), ACA Galleries (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Woodstock Artists Association (1963) (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - "Exhibition of Paintings by Anton Refregier," (1965), and Catalog We Make Our Tomorrow, 1964-1965 (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - "Anton Refregier" (1966), Harbor Gallery, 1966-1969 (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - "Exhibition of Paintings by Anton Refregier," (1967), Hermitage Museum, Leningrad (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - "Leningrad Graphic Workshop," (1967), ACA Galleries, 1961, 1966-1967 (Box 18, Folder 39)
  - "Anton Refregier: Paintings," (1967) and Lecture, Rudolph Galleries, 1965-1970 (Box 18, Folder 40)
  - "Peace, War and the Freedom Struggle," (1968), ACA Galleries (Box 18, Folder 41)
  - ACA Galleries (1973) (Box 18, Folder 42)
  - Berlin, German Democratic Republic (1974), 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 43)
  - "New York WPA Artists, Then and Now," (1977), Parsons School of Design (Box 18, Folder 44)
  - "Chile" (1979, 1980), Moscow, Samarkand, Soviet Union (Box 18, Folder 45)
  - Anton Refregier Memorial Exhibition (1981), Woodstock Artists Association (Box 18, Folder 46)